resume.md 2024-07-24

MICKAEL REIS

João Pessoa - PB, Brazil • mickaelyoshua@gmail.com • LinkedIn • Instagram • GitHub

Data Analysis • Data Engineering

Hi, my name is Mickael Yoshua. I have strong experience with Data Engineering and Data Analysis. I have contribue building and managing two Data Bases for the Paraíba's Court of Accounts, made several reports using Python and SQL bringing differents insights about the economic situation of cities and states through Statistical Analysis and use of Indicators and created dashboards in QlikView for better data visualization and analysis.

I'm seraching for new oportunities to grow and contribue in Data professional area and hope that you'll consider me to a spot so we can work together

SKILLS

- Back-End: FastAPI, TDD, Pytest;
- Data Analysis / Business Intelligence: QlikView, Statistics, Probability, Data Visualization;
- Data Science: Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow;
- Data Engineering: Amazon Web Service (AWS), Pyspark, PostgreSQL, SQL Server;
- Others: Git, Python, C++, SQL, Web Scraping, Docker.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intern in Data Analysis - Jun 2022 to Present

Intership at Court of Auditors of Paraíba, located in João Pessoa - PB.

- Build and Manage Relational Database;
- Build dashboards for data analysis and for Auditors to consult;
- Extract, Transform and Load data (ETL) to feed dashboards and analysis reports;
- Web Scraping scripts.

Contribute to analysis of public invoids (medicine and hospital material) by making SQL scripts to feed a QlikView dashboard; Automate the extraction of data from DATASUS, from that transform and load the data into a Relational DataBase and a QlikView Dashboard; Multiple analysis and reports on data.

Intern in Electrical Distribution Projects Design - Sep 2020 to Jun 2022

Intership at Engeselt, located in João Pessoa - PB. Service of design and budget of eletrical distribution projects for Energisa-MS.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

resume.md 2024-07-24

The ideia came when I was studying a course about finances and one of the first instructions was to track you expenses and incomes. I searched different apps to do that but wasn't satisfyed, so I started developing my own.

A ideia veio de quando eu estava participando de um curso de finanças e uma das primeiras instruções foi registrar despesas e receitas, não me senti muito satisfeito com os apps que eu ia encontrando para isso então decidi fazer o meu próprio.

Web API developed to CRUD operations (Create, Read, Update e Delete) in PostgreSQL database created to register expenses and incomes of differents users. FastAPI and SQLAlchemy to develop an assynchronous application, tests with Pytest, Docker to run and manage the app's execution environment and the database itself and Github Actions to atomated tests.

ETL of public Companie's Data

Automatic PostgreSQL DataBase builder using Docker. Extract, Transform and Load data from Brazil's Receita Federal (data made available by the Governmet). This project was made with Docker, Python and PostgreSQL using Asynchronous I/O, Synchronous Programming, Asynchronous Programming (Processes and Threads) and OOP (Object Oriented Programming). Initial idea is be able to get the contact os companies using different filters such as CNES, region, status etc.

Instagram Bot

An Instagram robot using selenium webdriver to collect data from user posts (number of likes, publication date, text of comments, text of description, link of publishment) and get list of followers and followings. The goal is collect the data to make a sentiment analyses about the interaction with every post and keep track of who stoped following the user.

EDUCATION

- Completed Technitian in Mechanics and High School at IFPB Campus João Pessoa (2014-2017);
- Incomplete styudy in Electrical Engineering at IFPB Campus João Pessoa (2018-);
- Studying Compute Science at UNIPÊ (2024-).

Certificates